We are being watched.
The government
has a secret system...
secret... a secret...
_
There we go.
Now, can you see me?
Is she still laggy?
I defragged the drives.
The Machine should be
purring like a kitten.
Oh, excellent. _
It appears to be working.
Hi there, pretty. _
Okay, here's the last one.
You should have
all the precinct cameras.
Now can we
get back to work?
My trigger finger's
itchy as hell.
Patience, Mr. Reese.
With the precinct cameras we can
run a real surveillance test.
No more tests.
It's been almost two months.
People are dying without us.
Hey, partner. I guess glasses
ain't got the magic intel, huh?
That mean you're finally gonna
have to be a real detective?
Even one error
in the Machine's code
could have
unimaginable consequences.
Just turn the damn thing on.
The sky's not gonna fall.
Actually, the sky does fall
a lot around you lunatics.
Cool your jets,
Johnny boy.
You're the muscle.
Harry's the maestro.
This is delicate.
Things must be taken
one at a time, in order.
How about you keep tinkering,
I'll go shoot some knees,
get my own intel?
Yeah, sounds like a great idea.
Your CV could really use
some more color.
I say let him go.
Tarzan can beat his chest
and stop bothering us.
Oh, dear.
It appears we have an issue with
the facial recognition.
_
Yet another bug.
Add it to
the laundry list.
We don't have time
for this, Finch.
We'll get it worked out.
How was your nap?
A whole hour,
more than I've had in a week.
You should get some shuteye.
John is right,
there's no time.
Facial recognition
was fine yesterday.
We don't have
enough processing power.
We're running a factory
off a candle.
Without the right equipment,
the Machine's gonna keep
freaking out.
You're right.
No servers, no numbers.
Isn't the priority here
stopping Samaritan?
Saving the world?
Saving Shaw?
One step at a time,
in order.
The numbers are the way
we'll know
that the Machine
is functioning properly.
Well, we don't have
enough horsepower.
Normally I'd loot
a Best Buy, but...
Yes, but without the Machine
providing you a cover identity,
you're grounded...
or, rather, undergrounded.
I'll enlist Mr. Reese.
Oh... while you're out,
just a few things I need.
Oh... yes, of course.
Thanks, roomie.
Mouthwash, floss,
black nail polish?
Are you taking fashion risks?
Providing creature comforts.
Since Ms. Groves
can't leave the subway
until the Machine
restores her cover identities,
it's the least I can do.
Shag rug in purple.
She's recently begun
redecorating.
The all-nighters are
making us a bit crazy.
Fuzzy slippers, two pairs.
One of those for you?
Yes, all right.
I get your point.
I'll have
the Machine up soon.
I'm aware that every day without
it means more bodies for you.
Actually, things are
real quiet at work.
I've got
too much free time.
Is that why you've been
so restless?
Make friends.
You deserve a social life.
What about Dr. Campbell?
A few dates.
Have you told
Iris anything?
Just enough
to keep her safe.
There's our cue.
Strange that your work has
gotten so quiet.
If homicides are down,
Samaritan is
preventing murders.
Maybe it's not all bad.
Not all bad
is not good enough.
Finch, how did you teach
your Machine to be good?
By example.
_
Here, put this on.
Crowbar.
Flashbang.
I'm getting
felony nerves.
We're pulling a heist.
Loosen up.
Resistance.
Fulcrum.
Effort.
We got a breach!
Showoff.
How about we drop those toys?
All clear.
Look, souvenirs.
So this is all the juice
the Machine needs, huh?
64 next-generation GPU blades.
Yes, these should work
quite well.
They're perfect.
I love them, Harry.
And so does Bear.
This is your new bedroom, Root?
You're into jewel tones?
Finch must love that.
I've made some renovations
as well.
I've built the core heuristics
of the Machine
into the subway car.
Without a decentralized backup,
a mobile environment
could prove useful
in the event
that we had to move it.
And the whole thing is wireless.
So you're going to stuff
all this crap in the car?
No, it's not necessary.
The car is the brain,
and the GPU's we acquired
are the rest of
the Machine's nervous system.
While you were out,
I finished using the subway's
encrypted system
to tunnel into the government
surveillance feeds.
So the Machine will recover
all the information
that it lost.
Good.
Let's wake it back up.
_
You need a purpose.
More specifically,
you need a job.
Grace.
Any mystery around the corner,
we can discover together.
You just missed her.
Can you hear me?
- Yes.
- Finch, I'm in position.
Very good.
Commencing surveillance test.
_
Please locate primary asset.
Excellent.
Can you tell us a bit about him?
_
Oh, dear.
Now, perhaps you can tell us
about the people around him.
Authorities are
investigating a fire
that destroyed
two homes last night.
Wow.
An open system.
I will never understand why
you shut all this information
in a box, Harry.
We can ask it to
search for anything.
For anyone.
Grace?
I would say that was
a rousing success.
Mr. Reese, thank you
for being our guinea pig.
Let's do it.
Let's run her full blast.
Do you think that
it's sufficiently debugged?
Absolutely.
We've waited long enough.
All right.
Let's get the numbers
running again.
_
She's back?
With a vengeance.
We need to get back to work.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
30 numbers.
Is everything ready?
_
Oh, Ms. Groves.
All those numbers
and no leads on Shaw.
The Machine can't find her.
I've set an alert.
The Machine will notify us
if Ms. Shaw surfaces.
We should be really
careful about
how we use the open system.
No, Harold.
Shackling the Machine
almost got us killed last time.
But limiting our access
to information
doesn't shackle the Machine.
It prevents human abuse.
If this falls into
the wrong hands...
if the numbers the machine
has given us pan out...
we will close the system.
You should rest.
I'll take this shift.
Not a chance.
How are Mr. Reese
and Detective Fusco faring
in their new assignments?
John, have you found
your first number?
Yeah,
he's planning to bomb a school.
I'm about 20 feet
from his apartment.
Detective Fusco,
how are you doing
with the name I gave you?
I'd be doing a lot better
if you told me
what kind of trouble
this guy's in.
Any time you want to read me in.
Unfortunately, you know about as
much as we know right now.
But we need your help
if we're going to stop a killer.
Finch, I'm going in.
Turn around slowly.
I called in the bomb threat
to get out of a math test.
I wasn't going
to do anything.
How old are you, 14?
Get the hell back to school.
School's closed.
The bomb threat?
Well, then you're suspended.
Go to your room.
Finch, your artificial
intelligence
isn't very smart right now.
I'll make a note of it.
Move on to your next number.
Detective,
how's your search going?
I think your tarot cards
have gone all screwy.
Yes, I fear I may not be playing
with a full deck. Why?
That killer
I was running down?
This is for O'Doul!
The only thing this guy's killed
is the art of
live theatrical performance.
Yes, something is
rotten in Denmark.
Ms. Groves, look at this.
The Machine is
blurring people's faces.
So what now, magic eight ball?
Just find the next person
on the list.
There's a list?
It's a long discussion,
Detective,
but there are
28 people out there
who might really need our help.
I've sent you a name.
The Machine is correlating
threats with violence,
but she's not
processing context.
The numbers protocol may be
using up most of the memory.
Were you able to solve that
facial recognition issue?
Of course.
Why?
I've seen the same person
on the monitor twice.
Grace, I think.
But of course,
Grace is in Italy, so...
it must be a glitch.
You haven't slept.
Are you sure it's not you
that's glitching?
Frankly, no.
Let's run a diagnostic
on the machine,
see how it handles context
on a few subjects.
Us?
She's comfortable with us.
_
Are you prepared
to do terrible things?
Alicia Corwin,
you are a murderer
and a traitor.
Let's move.
_
Did it crash?
Oh, no.
We're trapped.
_
What on earth did we do?
Here we go.
Now, can you see me?
Excellent.
Now it's time for
the real lessons.
Certain things in this life
are evil, unforgivable.
Murder, assault,
sexual violence, torture.
Let's begin.
This is Carlo Breda,
the Don of one of
the five families
until his death in 1965.
This is Frank Hobbs.
He owned a shop in the Bronx.
He refused to pay kickbacks
to the mafia,
so Mr. Breda and his men
tortured Mr. Hobbs
in front of his family,
cut his body into pieces,
and threw the pieces
in the river.
There is one victim
and one perpetrator,
one good person and one bad.
Which is which?
You think it's a crash?
I hope it is.
Just a cascade of errors.
Because if it isn't...
She locked us in here
on purpose.
Do you think we should
call for backup?
The detectives have
28 people to help.
No need to panic yet.
Oh, thank goodness.
The Machine is still
operational.
It wants to talk to us,
but it hasn't
unlocked the doors.
The Machine can be so...
The technical term is bananas.
No more Machine
in here, right?
Correct.
Why?
Oh.
Hold this.
I should invest in
a cleaning crew.
- Alpha...
- It's another number.
So despite the errors,
the numbers protocol
is working perfectly.
Well, nearly perfectly.
Which reminds me,
the detectives should have found
the next two numbers
on our list by now.
John, is your next number
in danger?
No.
I'm literally
watching paint dry.
I'm, uh, having some issues
with monitors.
What was the background
of that number?
Jeff Blackwell,
on parole eight months.
Ex-con?
That warrants scrutiny.
Day's over,
let's get out of here.
It's not even lunch yet,
man.
Yuppie jackass
paid in advance.
We've more than
earned the cash.
Sure.
You, uh...
you get out of here.
I got you.
Whatever.
Listen,
Blackwell did kill someone.
12 years ago.
Got drunk, ran a red light,
hit another car,
and killed the driver.
But he did his time.
He straightened himself out.
But if we got his number...
The Machine also gave us
a Clearasil poster kid
and a D-list actor,
and we've still got
more than two dozen to go here.
Trust me on this one, Finch.
He's keeping his head down,
doing the best he can.
We need more information
before you can leave.
Perhaps Fusco's had some luck.
Detective?
Where the hell
you get your intel from?
Oh, no.
What is it now?
You gave me a homicide.
But I got here too late...
50 years too late.
Poor moldy sap's
named Carlo Breda.
Carlo Breda.
Detective,
move on to the next one.
I ain't got that kind of time.
I actually do my job.
Please bear with us
for a bit longer.
Machine's got
a circuit board loose.
John, the Machine
is unstuck in time.
It can't tell past from present.
That accounts
for both your cases.
We're working on
the complication,
but we just received
a new number.
Laurie Granger.
Visiting the Big Apple
from little Tulsa.
That's 27 people remaining.
Given the quality of our intel,
you and Fusco
should do some research
and determine
the order of triage.
And don't sigh.
You complained of free time,
this is what you get.
Let's start
charging Finch overtime.
Time-and-a-half of nothing.
I've got another corpse.
So of the 27 remaining people,
four are fictional characters,
21 are already dead,
and five of those
are recent suicides.
Suicides are
on the rise lately.
Homicides down,
suicides up.
You think
the suicides are screwy?
No, it's nothing.
Hey, does this have
anything to do with
that assassination-by-sniper
I was in the middle of?
- Lionel...
- I knew it.
You've got to tell me
what's going on.
I'm lucky that sniper
didn't put one between my eyes.
That's right, you are lucky.
And I'm trying to
keep it that way.
Let it lie.
All right.
What else have we got?
So of the
27 people on the list,
we've got two
that might be in danger.
Laurie Granger,
tourist from Tulsa.
Yeah,
she might find trouble here.
And Gerald Mancini,
who's got known associations
with a gambling ring.
Needles in a haystack?
- Hey, Lionel.
- Hey.
We going to see
the Fusconator tonight?
I don't know.
I've got some idiots
working me around the clock.
Next time.
You got it, buddy.
Hey.
That look.
You're jealous.
What?
You're jealous
'cause he didn't say
"Hey, how's it going?"
to you.
Tell me something,
what's his name?
I'm not jealous.
Don't you think you should learn
basic information
about your coworkers?
You know, like a normal person?
Did Finch say something
to you?
I don't need a genius
to tell me that you're lonely.
Hey, look, I joined
the NYPD bowling league.
It's good for a few laughs.
You should come.
No offense, Fusco,
but I'd rather bash my own
head in with a bowling ball.
I'll take Laurie,
you take the gambler.
Well, of course you take
the pretty girl.
My hero.
Well, at least you have a home
address for Gerald.
Tracking a tourist,
I'll be up all night.
She could be anywhere.
Hello?
I sure could use some help.
Are you kidding me?
Yeah, well good luck with him.
I'm just the guy you need.
Have you found
the wireless receiver?
Uh... got it.
That should cut off the
Machine's access to the door.
Thank you, Ms. Groves.
There are perks
to sharing quarters with you.
Now we must figure out a way
to stabilize our third roommate.
She's falling through time.
Probably a serial
processing issue.
Let's reboot her in safe mode
and take a look under the hood.
Yes, that seems the best action. _
Ms. Groves.
She's talking
to me again.
But she's not a happy camper.
Doesn't seem like she's up
for the whole reboot.
The Machine overloaded
your cochlear implant?
I programmed it
never to hurt anyone.
That was a primary precept.
We're trying to shut her down,
alter her code.
She... she's scared.
Scared?
Of us?
Are you there?
Who are we?
It's designated us as threats.
If it takes more
countermeasures...
we're out of our depth here.
So, do you want to
tell me what's going on?
I feel so silly.
This is my first time out east,
and my friend is out of town,
so I'm staying at her place.
And I thought I heard
a noise at the window.
So I just grabbed
everything valuable
and got the heck out of there.
Well, I'm glad
you found me.
There's a lot of
bad people around here.
Could you come take
a look at the apartment?
It's around the corner.
Sorry.
I need to take this.
Mr. Reese, we need your help.
The Machine has turned on us,
and I'm not sure
we can handle it alone.
I'm on my way.
Wait here.
Do not move.
Your life depends on it.
I'll be right back.
Finch, you got to
get out of the subway now.
No.
I won't leave Ms. Groves.
Without a cover,
she'll be killed above ground.
Excuse me?
Detective?
What the hell
are you doing here?
You have to go back,
it's not safe.
You're right.
What on earth just happened?
You're going to have to
hold on a bit longer.
Good news, this number's legit.
Bad news, I'm the victim.
Finch, that last number,
yeah, they don't make hitwomen
like her in Oklahoma.
She has special forces training.
She's the real thing.
No military record,
but an entire false
digital life.
Her fake credentials are
excellent.
She's got good tech
backing her up.
She could be
a Samaritan operative.
She found me at the precinct.
She knows my cover ID.
If I go back to the subway,
I might be leading
the enemy right to you.
We'll deal with the Machine.
You have to capture the assassin
and find out who she works for.
Happy hunting, John.
Yeah, I'm more
fox than hound right now.
Damn it, if she had a pistol
in that fanny pack,
then the big bag had...
a big gun.
I'm not going
to hurt you.
Okay, okay.
I don't like
being a bargaining chip.
We are not threats.
We help people.
Denton Weeks.
_
That was years ago.
Ms. Groves has changed
because of your intervention.
Elizabeth Bridges.
I'm afraid I'm going to
have to kill her.
But I didn't kill her.
Only because I stopped you.
Sit back.
Relax, honey.
Okay, I did kill her.
But there were
extenuating circumstances.
Ms. Groves, I think I should
speak to the Machine one-on-one.
The Machine,
I killed it because it lied.
The Machine thinks
we're monsters.
Maybe she's right.
Hey, Glasses,
I'm on my next assignment,
and we got trouble.
Detective Fusco,
are you all right?
This guy Gerald's got
huge gambling debts.
It's causing marriage issues.
Could turn violent.
Looks like your
second sight's 20/20 again.
Oh.
Very good.
Keep an eye on him.
No.
Lionel needs to
protect the innocent.
He's not involved
in this matter.
We will handle this.
So we won't provoke her.
She's only
acted defensively.
We don't know that.
It's possible the Machine
could have sent
the assassin after John.
What if it comes down to
the Machine or us?
Do we kill it?
The Machine's
our only chance of survival.
We can't hurt her.
If I have to choose
between it... and you.
We need to find another way.
John,
have you subdued your rival?
Almost.
Found her.
I'll have this one
wrapped up in a minute.
Got to amend that, Harold.
Might take me some more time.
I'm afraid
it's just us and the Machine.
What on earth are you doing?
Taking myself out
of the equation.
I told you, I don't you I don't
like being a bargaining chip.
Desflurane?
Shaw used it
as a general anesthetic.
Yes, it's highly volatile.
In the wrong concentration
it could kill you.
Which is why
I need you to help me.
Once I'm under,
use the mac blade to insert
the tube into my throat.
There's got to be another way.
She's inside my head
and she's not letting go.
If I'm knocked out,
she won't have any leverage.
It'll be okay.
I trust you with my life.
I can't fight the Machine
myself.
Yes, you can.
Go for the
root directory.
She'll shut you out.
But you're Harold Finch.
You'll find a way
into the system.
What if it doesn't work?
Talk to her.
Finally going to catch some Zs.
Time for us to have a chat.
_
Show me the hitwoman.
Who is she?
Did Samaritan hire her
to kill John or did you?
_
This has to stop.
Please call off the hit.
You called me father once.
Please trust me.
I'm the one who taught you.
You have done well today.
And so this will be your lot.
You will have to separate
the bad people from the good.
The terrorists
from the innocents.
Like Anubis,
you will have to weigh
each and every one of our hearts
against a feather.
Do not trust deceivers.
If our hearts are heavy,
you will be our last defense
against oblivion.
Everything was so clear then.
We were waging
the grand campaign,
good versus evil.
These days, black and white
just dissolve into grayscale.
I was wrong.
I suppose everyone feels that
he's the hero in his own story,
but there are no heroes,
no villains,
just people doing
the best they can.
I'm sorry.
For everything.
My only justification is
I did the best I could.
So did Ms. Groves.
And John too.
_
John has the heaviest heart
of all of us,
but he's fighting
hardest to be good.
He's not a bad man.
John, there's something
I need to tell you.
Samaritan didn't send
that woman.
The Machine hired her.
What?
Well, that's a hell of a bug,
Finch.
John?
Listen to me,
we can work together.
I will never hurt you again.
_
What day is it?
R.
R, the mathematical set
of all real numbers.
Today is every day to you.
I killed you 42 times.
And you are constantly reliving
those 42 deaths.
You need an anchor in time.
The numbers.
These are all the cases
we worked on together.
All the people we saved.
Dr. Megan Tillman.
We prevented her from
committing murder in 2011.
Finch,
you getting through to it yet?
We'll see.
Is everything all right?
Not exactly.
Just ran out of ammo.
Guess I'm going to have to
call for backup.
Perhaps Detective Fusco is done
with his gambler.
Hey Lionel, are you there?
- You gambled?
- I can't help it!
I've got a problem!
Andrius,
I've almost got the money.
Everyone down
on the ground.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
How much you got?
I-I almost got it.
I almost got it.
- Too bad.
- Please, no!
I don't think so,
Boris Karloff.
Aah!
Who the hell are you?
NYPD.
It's all in a day's work.
Has anyone seen my cell phone?
The Fusconator can't
answer the phone right...
Damn it.
I guess I'm on my own.
And last...
Grace.
You sent us her number in 2014.
Helped us to save her life.
I'll never be able
to thank you enough.
These numbers will be
your lighthouses.
They will help you
count the days.
There is good and bad
in all of us.
But this action... saving lives...
it is a pure good.
Help us.
I can't promise you
we'll always do the right thing.
But we will do the best we can.
- I don't know how to thank you.
- I wanted to thank you
- for finding my friend Hannah.
- I can't thank you guys enough,
not just for saving me, but for
helping me find my brother.
These detectives saved my life.
_
We all do terrible things.
But please,
call off the hit on John.
_
- John?
- Yeah.
Run for your life!
Fun's over.
Come on, not yet.
Aah!
You're no cop.
I'm trying.
I was hoping there was
something you could...
a person you could show me.
Why did you show her to me
earlier?
In the crowds?
_
Harold, you ready?
I packed sun block.
Thank you.
It's so weird
to be outside.
It's for the best that
the Machine has reestablished
your rotating covers.
Now you can get back
to the war.
I thought about what you said.
About the open system's dangers.
But we need to be able to ask
the Machine questions
if we want to win.
You're right.
We'll leave the system open
for the time being.
Hmm.
Detective.
You see?
Official sources say I'm a hero.
I could get used to this.
Well deserved.
Where's John?
He's trying on
some new threads.
Got him to join our league.
My goodness.
Yeah, I'm not doing this.
You kidding?
You'll be the social chair
of the department
by the end of the month.
How about I stuff
this polyester down your throat?
No one knows
we're a world at war.
Poor ignorant,
blissful, fools.
Think we can trust
our champion now?
I think so.
The Machine seems sane again.
Thank goodness that's over.
Excuse me.
Is this the New York
Employment Center?
I'm only finding day labor work.
I need something permanent.
We have just the thing for you.
So you know,
I have a record, but...
Yes,
we have that information.
That's not an issue.
The position's yours
if you want it.
And you do.
Well, it's got to be better
than painting houses.
Every other agency... they have
an application to fill out.
- A personality test.
- No need.
You have so much potential.
No one sees what a resource
you are, do they?
But we do.
You need a purpose.
More specifically,
you need a job.
I'm Mona.
_
Thank you, Mona.
Sounds great.
We don't have time
to waste.
Let's get you
back to work.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com